Hi, I wanted to talk about the Laplacian mesh deformation
and how you could use that to not only deform a mesh
but also deform an animation in this case.
We will go through the basic step
of the mathematics behind Laplacian deformations
and we will see how we can grow the system of equations
with more constraint up to the point
that it will be useful for animations also.
Laplacian deformations, first thing I will do
It's important in my libraries.
And when we talk about the Laplacian,
it's a system that works on a graph.
And so what we will have is that we will define a mesh
as being a bunch of vertices connected through edges.
And that could be seen as a graph, basically.
And my vertices will be in R3, because I'm
x, y, z coordinate in 3D dimensions.
And I will build a Laplacian matrix
using the normal descriptions that says that basically the Laplacian is the degree matrix
minus the adjacency matrix. And what are those? The adjacency matrix says which vertices is connected
to which vertices. So if I have five vertices inside of my mesh, I will have a matrix of five
by five. And for every vertex that I connected, so if my vertex two is connected to vertex three,
it means that in my matrix at row 2 column 3 I would have a 1 and at row 3 column 2 I would
have a 1 also. So basically just saying which vertices are connected to which one. And the degree
matrix is a diagonal matrix that in the diagonal just has the number of connections a vertex has.
So if my vertex number zero has five connections, it means that in position zero zero I would have five.
And the Laplacian is computed by just doing the degree minus the adjacency matrix.
So for instance I will have these functions that compute the degree matrix from the adjacencies,
because that's fairly easy to just sum the rows to see how many connections you have.
And I have a little function that generates Laplacian, it's just a strip mesh
with all the edges making squares and that's it.
and that's it. So all my vertices are a bunch of squares connected together.
And so, and it will compute for me, it will return the Laplacian, the adjacencies and the vertices.
And I have a bit big functions that just draw any mesh you throw at it, just by giving him the
list of vertices and the adjacency matrix, you can draw it in the entry D. So if I just display this
functions, you will see that I will have the generic Laplacian and I can draw
and I'll give me this trip. I've just generated it with my function.
So why do we talk about the Laplacian coordinates?
It's basically what we're interested in doing is to be able to deform a mesh but keep all the
little deformations between the vertices to keep it the same. So try to deform the mesh as
global but keep the details. And the Laplacian coordinates are the delta of your vertex.
So if you know the position of all your vertices, what you do is that you take,
for each vertex, you check all the vertices that are connected to it through an edge,
you make the average of that, and you do your vertex minus that average. So the delta is just
knowing how much offset you have between your positions
and the average positions of all your neighbor.
That's the Laplacian coordinates.
And why we computed the Laplacian matrix,
it's because that formula could be written
as a matrix multiplication.
It is just the Laplacian matrix multiplied by your vertex
and that give you the deltas.
What we want to do when we deform now,
As I said, we try to deform the mesh as a global,
but we also try to keep the little difference
as close as possible.
So what we want to do is to say that the delta VI prime,
so the deform delta mesh,
is exactly as close as possible
as the deform delta mesh originally.
So even if I deform my mesh,
all the little details I'm trying to make them stay the same.
So that's what we try to do as an error functions.
We try to say the difference between the deform mesh
and the original mesh is as small as possible.
So what you try to do is to minimize that error.
And if you write it as a matrix formulations,
that means that we try to minimize these functions.
And if I try to minimize these functions,
mean that because it's a square it's fairly easy it just means that I need to take the
derivative of that function and set it equal to zero and basically because a bunch of conditions
on the shape of the Laplacian matrix you could actually simplify this down to say
what we're trying to solve is just to say that the delta vi equal delta v and that's
This is a system of linear equation because Lv is known, it's my delta, L is my big matrix
of coefficients and V' are the position of the vertices I'm looking for.
So that's a linear system of equations.
And I can solve it through a least square system just as is.
So for instance I take my functions I do L dot V to get my delta and I just give that
to a least square solver saying that I get the Laplacian as A and I get the position
of my vertex as B, or my delta, sorry.
But deltas are in three dimensions, so actually I have to solve for x, y and z separately.
So that's what I'm doing here, x, y and z separately.
And if I don't give them anything else, it just tries to find the best solution with
all the deltas and has no other info.
So what happens is basically, it's useless in this case, but it just re-centered the
entire machine zero zero.
So that's just saying, serve the laplacian while there is basically nothing to serve.
So what we want to do is to grow that system and says but there is a bunch of vertices
that I want to anchor in some positions.
So what you do is that you grow the system by having all the Laplacian on top and then
you grow the matrix with all the constraints you want to add.
And in this case the constraint is just saying I want this vertex number x to be in that
position.
So it's mandatory that one needs to be there.
So that constraint function is just saying for every vertex that I will want to lock,
I will make a row of zeros for every vertices that exist, and I just put a one in the vertex
I'm trying to lock.
And then the D there will be the true positions of the vertex I want to have, because that's
what it says, it says vertex number five, for instance, will be in 0, 0, 0, that's it.
So that's what I will be doing here.
I will build a matrix that will be the length of all the vertices that exist and I will just
set that my first constraints will constrain the first vertices and the second constraint
will constrain the last vertex and then I will have the positions for those two vertices that
I want to force and that's it. I grow my system by stacking the two matrices on top of each other
and I concatenate the two um deltas and the positions and then again I solve for x y z
and now we get what I asked for I basically said I want to pin the first vertex here
and the last vertex over there and you see you get a nice curved shape so it works for two
it works of course for three and so many as many anchors you're trying to to solve
it tries to minimize the amount of errors of everything, so it tries to minimize the error
of the vertices and the Laplacian deformations at the same time, which is why you get this shape here.
Now, I've solved everything using the least square solver from SciPy.
Basically, if you try to solve normally a least square, there is the pseudo inverse that you
you could use formulations.
So instead of, if you have an A dot X equal B,
which is exactly what I have,
I get the L dot V equal delta.
So it's the same formula.
And if I try to minimize the square distance of that,
the formulations through a bunch of computations,
you could derive this formula here
that would say that you get the A transpose A equal X
equal h transpose b and so that's something
that you could solve directly now.
It's not a least square problem anymore.
The dimensions of those two matrix matches
so you could do a true solve.
So if you wanted to do a solve,
usually what you do is that you inverse your a matrix
and you multiply your b by it and that give you your x.
So that's how you solve it numerically.
So what I will do is that I will build this matrix
to show you and solve it using a solver
instead of a least co-solver now.
So basically, I've done exactly the same.
I've got my A and right hand side.
And so I do the A transpose A
and I do the A transpose B for the X, Y and Z separately.
Again, I do have to do it separately
for the three dimensions.
And what it gives me is exactly the same answer.
There is no difference.
I've done a difference that I haven't done a least square.
Now I've done the solve through matrix multiplications.
The issues usually with this formulation
because that kind of work and in this case it works
is that it's not numerically stable
in the if the system is big,
it's not exactly solvable. So that's one way of formulating it and there is another way to do it
is to do the more pen rows pseudo-inverse. Basically again without going too much in details
it will allow you to solve these issues by replacing the A transpose A inverse by the
the pseudo, the main rows, pseudo-inverse,
that goes through a singular value decomposition,
and that's way more stable to solve this kind of stuff.
So now you could solve it just by doing,
so as before, compute my delta, my A, my right-hand side,
combine all of them.
And instead of doing all the different math,
I would do the pseudo-inverse,
and the Penrose inverse from the NumPy or SciPy libraries.
And it works also.
It will give you, again, exactly the same answer,
but this one is way more stable numerically.
Now, be careful that it looks like
haven't solved x, y, z separately.
It's just because in NumPy and SciPy,
all those dot projects are multi-dimensional.
So it did solve x, y, z,
But he did it in parallel for me and returned it XYZ parallel, but it was still solved separately
It still solved XY and Z separately
Now one thing you've noticed and as I said it quickly
What it tries to do here it tries to solve
For all the constraints we gave him so we told him you have to make sure that your lagrange
range, multipliers, your deltas stays as close as possible and you have to try to make sure that
you pin your vertices where I ask you to do it. The only stuff is that he's trying to minimize
the amount of errors that all of that is bringing. So you could see that he hasn't pinned the vertices
where I asked him to do it. He minimized the amount of error, but it was not perfect.
But if you have a need, your vertex is to be pinned exactly at some places, you will
have to go through another system of solving to say that you want to solve for the Lagrange
subject to a bunch of constraints, which is what we will want to do here with the Lagrange
multiplier this time.
And so normally the basic problem of the Lagrange multiplier says that you're still trying to
minimize a least square problem, but it's subject to a bunch of constraints, which is
the case of what we have here.
We have still LVE minus delta that we're trying to minimize, but the anchor positions are
constrained.
The Lagrange formulation for this problem, it says that you could add those two together
and inject in the middle a bunch of Lagrange multipliers there.
So it's the same formulations,
you just get the Lagrange multiplier in the middle.
And now if you try to minimize these issues,
what you have to do is to take the derivative
with respect to x, and I'll give you these formulations,
and you need to take the derivative
with respect to the Lagrange multipliers,
that give you those formulations, those functions.
And so all of that can be turned into one big linear system.
And the one big linear system is this one now,
is the ATA C transpose and then the C in the bottom zeros.
So basically that's the first line here
that you're trying to solve for A transpose B
and the C with the D here.
So it's all mapped into one big system.
Again, you see the formulation had before,
A transpose A, A transpose B,
but you're also growing it with a constrained transpose
and constrained and all that kind of stuff.
And if you solve this system now,
it would be exactly the same problem, right?
You get the L transpose L.
You get in response of zero blocks.
this one you get the constraint so you make a block matrix with the l transpose l the constraint
transpose the constraint and a bunch of zeros there and then you need to you could solve now
it's not a least square it's a real solve just to be careful that you've solved for x but also
for the Lagrange multipliers which I don't need so I'm only reading the vertices that's the only
part I need and so now if you solve it this way your anchors are constrained
and so they are really mapping at zero zero is exactly the positions you want
it so that's going through the KKT system KKT system from the Lagrange
multiplayer so you we've seen how to solve the Laplacian seen how to
constraint the Laplacian if you wanted to make it really constrained. Now there is one other thing
I've done every time that I said I've solved for x, y and z separately. And that's true,
the l.x is only for one dimensions. What we want to do now is to say could we solve for x, y, z
z at once. And so that we could do by growing the system of the Laplacian matrix using the
Kronecker product. And if you do this, basically what happens is that I will try to grow my
system by multiplying with the identity matrix of the size three because I have three vertices.
And what will happen when I do this is that if I had five vertices and I got values, you
you know, A, B, C, D, for instance, and E,
I go up to there, but let's say I have A, B, C,
and if I'm multiplied by the chronicle product,
basically I will have now my matrix
that will grow three times in the row
and the column dimension.
So instead of having A, B, C, I will have A00, B00, C00.
On the second row, I will have zero, B0,
zero a zero zero b zero zero c zero and then zero zero a zero zero b zero zero c so it makes the
abc diagonal every time and by doing so it gives me the same the same values but on a bunch of
different rows and so what i can do now is that instead of having my xyz as being xyz and versus
second xyz and so on. I can actually stack them with a transpose so I can have xyz xyz xyz xyz
inside of one big vector which is what I'm doing here with the v. I get the xyz xyz xyz
and so I get one line for the x one line for the y one line for the z and so on. So you grow the
entire system and you do the same for your ankles of course and for your positions so you grow
everything the same way. The only thing I will do here is that I will actually do something I
haven't done so far. I will add a weight to the anchor. And by changing the weights, you could
decide how much of the laplacian need to be solved, how much of the anchor need to be solved.
You could start to tweak values depending on each of the different stuff. So that's what I'm doing
doing here, I give an anchor weights of three,
building my Laplacian matrix as before.
Now I just have an identity matrix.
I do the chronicle product from the L,
I multiply my delta now with a flattened version
of vertices, so I will have x, y, z, x, y, z, deltas.
I do my anchor, also grow it.
And I also flatten my anchors
and I multiply the weights of the anchor
and the position by the weights
and that give me some constraint
on how close I want the object to be.
And now, I still have the same results.
The only difference is that I've solved for x, y, z
in one pass instead of having solved for x and n, y, n, z.
Now I have solved for x, y, z at once.
And I could do it for more vertices, more anchors, and so on.
And why am I interested in solving XYZ at once is that now I could start to think about
constraints that would act on XYZ at once and not act separately on a bunch of dimensions.
And one of the constraints we will be interested into adding into the system is to be able
to say that we want to lock some edge.
We want to say that some edges are not allowed to change.
And so for this, what we will do is that we say that we will have some edges before modifications
and after modifications they need to stay exactly the same length. So this is the same
problem that we had when we said the deltas needs to stay the same. Now what we have to say is that
the distances but the length of edges have to stay the same. And so what we have now is that we'll
have the hv and the h is an edge incidence matrix. So it's a matrix I would say that's the two edges
that are connected together and the thing that you do is that you put one vertex equal to one
and the other vertex equal to minus one because what we want to make sure that if one move in
one direction the other needs to move near the other directions to keep the length of an edge
the same length and the functions for knowing the length of the edge is this one here it depends
on the rest pose of the original length you had and the current length you've computed.
Now the issue we have is that this formulation says that it depends on the distance of those edges
and basically what it means is that the distances are computed with the square of the values. So
So when we try to minimize the deltas,
it will, at the same time, update the length that actually
needs to be squared to know.
And so it's not a linear system of equation anymore.
You cannot solve this in one go.
What you have to do is to solve it once,
and then check the distance you have,
compute the amount of errors you had between your edge,
push in the system, solve again, and so on and so on.
So it's a system that will become now iterative
to fix the length, because you cannot do it in one pass.
So that's what we will do here.
I'll do it by growing all the system as 3D.
So I get the Laplacian 3D, my Delta 3D,
is my bunch of anchors, all stays the same.
And now I have my iterations here.
Basically, I will compute my h and the length of all my edges and how you do it is that you
compute the original length. You compute the new vector that gives you the new length.
You put the incidence matrix with 1 and minus 1, except that as I've done directly for the
anchors giving a bunch of weights I would do the same for the edge constraint say I get the length
that are uh instead of being just the one they actually have a weight so I've put the weight
and minus weight and then the length you want to compute is the original length divided by the new
length divided multiplied by our weight factor and you get the and the vector itself that's
that multiply this.
And now, you don't only solve for the L and N curves,
you also solve for your H.
So you grow your system with all the constraints,
you solve with a least square, and you repeat,
and you repeat until you converge towards something.
So what I've done here is I said,
I have a bunch of edges, that's the edges I want to look,
that needs to stay the same.
And those edges are those four that are here.
So it tries to keep the length of those ones
as close as possible as what they were before,
while still doing everything else
that the system was doing.
And yeah.
So that's the length constraint.
That's one of the constraints
you could add to the system.
Another stuff that happens quickly when you try to do the Laplacian is this issue we have here is that
basically what I've done is that I've completely rotated my vertex there
but you could see that the Laplacian, the only thing it tries to do is try to deform the mesh
but keeping all the local translate so it can only skew your mesh basically that's
That's not anything it did.
It skewed my mesh to try to match this.
And it's probably not exactly the result
I was expecting with the strip.
When I said, take those two edges there
and rotate them by 90 degrees,
I would not expect that S shape.
What you could do in the Laplacian is grow this
into a system where what you try to do
that instead of minimizing the amount of error
with the deltas, you allow yourself
to consider every vertex as a system inside of a transform.
And it can rotate, and it can scale uniformly
before doing that comparison.
So you're trying to say, maybe you
will find a smaller error if actually you
had considered that everything just rotated 45 degrees.
And that's what the transform here would be.
The paper that talks about this one
is a Laplacian surface editing.
Let you read it if you want to go through the mathematics
behind how they derive all those formulas and the matrices
that we will use soon, where they come from.
It's all from this paper, so from the Laplacian surface
editing.
But basically, what you're trying to do
is to figure out what the transform you could find
in a delta at the same time as trying
to minimize everything else.
The advantage of this system is that what they found
is that you could solve for every vertex.
So for every delta, since there is a TI,
it's a different transform per delta. What you will want to do is to solve this system that
basically says a contains all those vertices, your vertices and the vertices of all your neighbor
and you stack them in the matrix like this one and if you solve that system for a x equal bi yb
will be the position um of the of the deformed position so bi is all the deformed positions
of your vertices ai is all the undeformed vertices positions and x what will return in
this case it will return the s h1 h2 h3 t x t y tz and what there are there are the matrix that
that's how the component of the matrix
that's allowed you to rotate and scale a mesh
as long as the rotations is small.
So it's an approximation of a rotation matrix.
So the S, C, S, H1, H1, H2, H3,
all goes into that big matrix here.
That is a transformation matrix.
So solving this system,
solving this system give you the transformation matrix
that's how you to be plugged in there as a solve.
Now, what is interesting to see is that to solve this,
again, we get our friend formula A transpose A,
say pseudo inverse, basically, through the pseudo inverse,
we could compute those x's.
And what is interesting is to see is that it depends,
B depends on the deform vertices,
Which means that what we have now is that before we had,
in this case we had the undeformed vertices
minus the deformed vertices.
Now we have something here that's taken into account
deformed vertices minus deformed vertices.
So they all talk about basically the same thing.
Which means that we could turn this weird formulation
say the T delta I minus Lv prime.
We can turn it as L minus transpose delta equal V prime.
So basically this stuff become my A matrix.
And we don't have Bs anymore here.
We just have zeros because we've never moved it
on the other side.
We never have the LV equal LV prime.
We moved everything on the left side
so we can jump off the zero to solve
and everything is recouped here
and I'll give you the V prime.
So the T can be just solved by solving this
without taking care of the BI.
And now you could solve all the systems.
So what it means, it means that you
have to pre-compute and solve the T for every vertices once,
and then you could solve your least square as usual.
So that's what I'm doing here.
I take every vertex that I have, compute that big matrix, that big A matrix with all my vertices
and my neighbors vertices. I do the pseudo inverse that gives me the S, H and T.
I multiply my transpose by my deltas and that gives me my new deltas and then finally I remove
it from my Laplacian and my L3 I removed my deltas and now basically now I have built this
matrix instead of L I have my L minus T deltas. So that's what you pre-compute once
and then you push that as your anchor, the anchor, you stack them as usual and so the
difference now is that you don't solve for deltas anymore, you solve for a bunch of zeros.
that's it you just have zeros to solve and you do your least square and if I do this
now you could see that I have
the deformations where he found out that it was better to actually rotate every
elements up to reach in the direction I want it and it curve my shape here
and also it scaled it because I give it something bigger you see that the first
The first square is bigger. It actually scaled the entire square to find out the best solution in this case.
So that was the interesting stuff of this paper, to be able to turn this into a transform issue.
Now I could have the transform and on top of it add my edge constraint.
And so what I would do is that I will say that I want all my strips in the middle to keep the same length.
And that's what I would try to solve.
So again, I compute all the adjacencies in the L.
And now I loop through my edges constraint
at the same time.
And what I get is this shape now.
So not only has it rotated,
it also has managed to keep the length of all my edges.
Now what I will do is I will take all the functions
rewrote and I will make one big function I can reuse and reuse every time I try to do a Laplacian
deformation. So those functions will be basically the fact that you could compute the rotation
and variance that transform for all the vertices and then you get the deform that salutes deform
your mesh choosing different algorithm different constraints and weights and all that kind of
stuff. So all of the options are inside of these deform functions now and I can reuse this function
see to play and see what we could use,
iterate to different number of iterations
for the edge constraint, remove the edge constraint,
remove the rotation and variance,
use art constraint or art constraint,
and use edge and so on and so on.
So all the options are tweakable
and you can play with them independently.
So now that I have a function that will allow me
to deform any type of mesh I could throw at it.
What I would do is that I would decide
to start to play with animation data instead of just
my bunch of vertices here.
So I will load my character, load my animation,
and I will pre-compute a bunch of foot contacts.
So I know when my foot are locked on the ground.
And I would just render this so we
see what we're talking about. So we just have this character walking along. And that's what I
will want to use and deform using the Laplacian deformation. So the first thing I have to do
is to convert my animation into a mesh, a Laplacian mesh. And so for this what I would do is I would
take the animation and I will take a bunch of bones and all those bones I will get the positions
in world space and I will take the positions of each of those bones for every frame and that will
be all my vertices so that will be the position of the bones at every frame and then you have to
build your adjacency matrix and the first adjacency matrix you will build is the skeleton
adjacencies just saying that yes okay my foot is connected to my leg my leg is connected to my
hips and so on and so on so that builds the the connections of the skeleton and I repeat that for
every frame using the Kronecker product again to put it as a diagonal product. So my adjacencies
so I'm getting from here is basically every pose at every frame are just connected the bones are
connected between them and that's it. Then I get another function if I want to connect
the bones together frame by frame so connecting my hips of frame and to my hips of frame and plus
one and my foot of frame and to my foot of frame and plus one and so on and so on and a function
to compute the laplacian out of it. And what I could do is then take my animation and I would take
just a small piece of the animation that moves forward and I get much greater
adjacencies, I connect to more of my animations frame and I compute my
Laplacian and I will anchor the first pose and the last pose and the way I
will anchor them is that I will take the ten first vertices, belongs to the first
pose and the ten last vertices, they will be exactly the same pose as the first
one, except that I will just shift them three meters in front. So that's what I'm building here.
And if I display this, and I would just remove the stuff there. What you have is this.
In black is the original animations. So every frame of the animation. And what you have in yellow
is the deformed animations that I've done. So you could see it was nearly working straight,
but just not straight and the first and last frame were not the same so you know I've locked the first
and last frame to be exactly the same so I can have a nicer loop let's say
now what we could see is by default I'm stretching the entire the entire animation a little
and say if you could see hey all my feet were probably having were anchored and I have all
all the positions at the right spot,
while this one now is sliding a little.
I have this, this one is more visible.
My default mesh is sliding.
So the first thing I would do is that I would add
a bunch of length constraint.
That was the reason why we wanted to have,
the ability to have length constraint is because now
I can add constraint inside of my animation.
And all the edge constraints I will do is I will say between the two and the foot.
If they were locked during the animation, so that's the foot tag is what I've computed
as when do I have contact.
If I have contact, I basically said that I want to lock the length between all those
frames.
I'm doing here and computing the length between of the all those frames and the
second constraint of length I will do at the same time is that I would say what
the length of the legs have to stay the same so I will basically say that for
every frame every leg has to keep the same length and same for the for the
foot so leg and foot have to stay the same all the time so if I turn the edge
constraint. You can see that everything is red, means that it's all the edge
constraint I have on the system. I have a lot of them and unfortunately it's hard
to see, but yeah, you get the constraint that is between the frames also.
So I'm only displaying the skeleton, I'm not displaying all the edges because you
get more edges, you get all the edges off between the frames also. But as
constraint you can see that it is it is there it's connected between them and
those one should be zeros so one of the constraint so I can crank up the
number of iterations it will do just to try to solve this a bit more and make
sure that when it slides it basically groups keeps all the foot at the same
time and move all of them at the same time. Another way you could have done this was to
not making edge constraint and just saying that all of those were the same vertex and
that pinning only one vertex but it will be harder at the later stage to recompute the animations
because you know I would not have just match for every frame but that would be another solution to
do it. The other things that I've also added is the way that I can say the height of the foot
has to stay the same exactly between original animations and the new animation. And now I've
done this just to say that instead of anchoring the the vertex by itself, now that I'm computing
everything as x, y, z. I'm only anchoring the y-axis and I says all the y-axis of the foot
has to stay the same. It can only move in x and z, but the y cannot change. So that's what
the use feet height means is that you pick all the height of the feet and it cannot change.
And now that I have deformed my animation the way I want it, I can go a little higher,
see if it's any difference. Now that I have deformed the animation the way I wanted, I can
regenerate animation out of it. And so how I would do this is I would take the original animations
and take the new vertices, the new positions and basically I can take the original animations to
know where what was the orientations and I can use all the position of the point, the vertex now
to recompute IKs, recompute the orientations of the hips and the kind of stuff. So I recompute
the hips orientation based on the position of the left and right leg and the height is between
the spine and the hips that I have. That gives me the new hips and I do the same for both feet
and I compute an IK between the two and so this allows me to recompute the animation so I can
compute animations out of the original animation and my new vertices. And that gives me this now.
I have my animation that match the new deformed Laplacian. So I've deformed my animations by
turning into a mesh, deforming the mesh and turning the mesh back into an animation.
And I can do all sorts of transformation this way.
What I will do is that now that I have something that goes straight,
what I want to do is to generate curved path animations out of this.
And so I will have a function.
So first thing first, I will make out the true animations out of the data.
So now I have a walk straight animation. It's a real anim for me.
and I have something that's allow me to say if I know that I have a path along a
straight line well I can bend that path so that's what this function does if if
I have a path that is straight and it points along that path I can
actually bend those points and do whatever I want with it and I can shift
them which I'll use also being able to bend in or bend out when you're bending.
And so I would take my animations, my walk straight animation now.
I will convert it as an aplation the same way.
And what I will do now is that I will anchor every single vertex of it because I will make sure that
all the vertices will bend using that curve function so basically I'm
anchoring every vertices and what I got is let's remove first is this if I
start to bend I'm bending all my meshes and I'm still solving for the
Laplacian and solving for mainly solving for the edge length that's what
would be interesting in this case because you could see now that my feet again are sliding
because of the transformation I just gave it to you to it so I would recall the exact same function
that says every bone has to keep the same length and every steps have to stay the same length
so that's a use edge it has a hard time at the beginning of the few iterations but if you start
to iterate and see that he can start to solve and figure out a curved path with the feet as
locked as best as it can and you could bend it as much as you wanted. What I've done also is that I
have bent the bottom and bent the top but shifted the top a little and depending on the angle so
as to lean in basically. And now that I have this, I could throw it a bit more, make sure
I have something fairly stable, and of course I can regenerate an animation out of it.
And I get my animations of the character bending and walking along the path and curved.
So that's probably a bit extreme, but that's the example. So this is what you could do with an
Applation you could deform a mesh and then of course if you can deform a mesh
you could try to turn your animation as a mesh and use it to deform your
animations. I hope you liked it and see you next time.